Finding Aid for the George Pullen Jackson Papers – faculty
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
George Pullen Jackson Papers – faculty
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0225
2.94 linear feet
Biography
George Pullen Jackson was born in Monson, Maine on August 20, 1874. He attended the Royal conservatory of music in Dresden, Germany during 1897-1898, Vanderbilt University during 1900-1901, and received a Ph.B. (1904) and a Ph.D. (1911) at the University of Chicago. In 1907-1908, he did graduate studies at universities in Munich and Bonn, Germany. Meanwhile, he was associated with the Houston Biscuit Company in Birmingham, Alabama, of which his father was president. He began his teaching career in 1905-1906, as an instructor in German at Kansas Agricultural College (later Kansas State University). He continued his teaching career at Case School of Applied Science (later Case Institute of Technology) (1906-1908), University of Chicago (1908-1910), Oberlin College (1910-1912), and Northwestern University (1912-1913). For the next five years he was assistant professor of German at the University of North Dakota, also serving at summer sessions at the University of Chicago in 1915 and 1916. In 1918 he joined the faculty of Vanderbilt University as associate professor of German, becoming professor eight years later and serving in that capacity until he retired in 1943 as professor emeritus. During 1946-1947 he served as interim professor of German at the University of Florida.
Aside from teaching, his chief interest was American folk music, particularly southern spirituals, on which he wrote and lectured extensively. He was the author of many books and articles, including The Rhythmic Form of the German Folk Songs, White Spirituals in the Southern Uplands and Spiritual Folk-Songs of Early America. With Charles Faulkner Bryan, he edited American Folk Music for High School and Other Choral Groups. He served on the board of advisory editors of Southern Folklore Quarterly and was for many years the music critic for the Nashville Banner and other southern newspapers. Jackson was a specialist in the music of the shape-note hymnals popular in the southern highlands, where he first encountered the Sacred Harp hymnals. In 1939 he organized the Tennessee Sacred Harp Singing Association, and he organized and managed the Old Harp Singers of Nashville, a concert group which toured the eastern United States and gave eighty concerts and broadcasts.
Jackson was a member of the Tennessee Music Teachers Association, the American Musicology Association, the International Folk Music Council, numerous folklore societies, the Modern Language Association, Sigma Alpha Epsilon, and Phi Beta Kappa.
In 1906, he married Inez Emeline Wight in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, and the couple had two children, Frances Helen (Parker)in 1908 and George Pullen (Jr.) in 1910. His first wife died in 1918, and he later married Lois Diantha Barnes in Chattanooga, Tennessee in 1926. Jackson died in Nashville, Tennessee on January 19, 1953.
Scope and Content Note
The George Pullen Jackson collection is divided into five series: Correspondence; Articles; Notes on Songs; Songs; and Phonographs and Tapes.
Series I contains both outgoing and incoming correspondence. Much of it relates to Jackson’s song collecting and arrangements for performances.
In Series II, there are articles by and about Jackson, as well as newspaper clippings and photographs.
The extensive Notes on Songs in Series III include research materials and printed songs. This series also includes a bibliography of Jackson’s publications, and a bibliography of Jackson’s collection of Southern Hymn books now held by the library of The University of California at Los Angeles. In seven boxes of note cards are tune indices, a bibliography of hymn and tune books, a directory of Sacred harp singers, a chronological file of hymn books, 1737-1839, excerpts from song books, and an alphabetical file of song titles.
Series IV consists of songs, song titles, and song fragments. There is an index of song titles and/or first lines and their location within the collection.
In Series V, there are 33 and 1/3 records, reel to reel tapes and cassette tapes of many of the songs Jackson collected. There is an index of the recorded songs and their location with in the collection.
- Correspondence- Outgoing, May 19, 1930-January 31, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence-Outgoing, June 10, 1943-December 18, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence-Outgoing, January 13, 1948-February 16, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence-Outgoing, February 25, 1948-July 3, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence-Outgoing, September 10, 1949-October 11, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence-Incoming---Burba-Bayard (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence-Incoming---Bayard-Bradfield (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence-Incoming---Bradfield (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence-Incoming---Bradfield (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence-Incoming---C., Richard-Chase (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence-Incoming---Danforth-English (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence-Incoming---Flanders-Jagendorf (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence-Incoming---Janson-Ludendorf (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence-Incoming---McDonald-Mells (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence-incoming---Metcalf-Peterson (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence-Incoming---Reschanback-Thompson (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence-Incoming---Wieand-Yoder (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Articles---“The 400 Year Odyssey of the ‘Captain Kidd’ Song Family” (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Articles---Judas Tune Family (Das Judaslied) (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Articles---Judas Tune Family (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Articles---“On Finding Out Just What That Tune Is” (an explanation of Jackson’s index card system) (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Articles---“On Song Types”; “The Pennsylvania Dutch Created and Sang Spirituals, Too” (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Articles---“Singin’ Billy”, ” Some Factors in the Diffusion of American Religious Folksongs” (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Articles---“Stephen Foster’s Debt to American Folksongs” (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Newspaper Articles---‘Southern Musicians”---Bailey-Croyton (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Newspaper Articles---“Southern Musicians”---Fabian-Lucchese (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Newspaper Articles---“Southern Musicians”---Martin-Sharlow (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Newspaper Articles---“Southern Musicians”---Stephens-Yergin (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Photos---Photos of Southern Musicians---Ballard-Breton (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Photos-Photos of Southern Musicians---Cadek-Lucchese (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Photos-Photos of Southern Musicians---Moore-Ross (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Photos-Photos of Southern Musicians---Rous-Wood (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Articles---“The Folklorist as Apostle of a Broader, Deeper Humanism; “ The American Amish Sing Medieval Folk Tunes Today” (Box 1, Folder 33)
- “Old Timey Country Singin’s”; “Did Spiritual Folk-Songs Develop First in the Northeast?” (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Collected Articles by George Pullen Jackson, 1908-1947, with a Prefatory Note by George Pullen Jackson (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Publications---Song Book---American Folk Music for High Schools and Other Choral Groups, 1947, Collected and Edited by George Pullen Jackson and Arranged by Charles Faulkner Bryan (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Research Materials---Printed materials, clipping (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Research Materials-Printed materials, clippings (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Research materials---Printed materials, clippings (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Research Materials---Printed materials, clippings (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Research Materials---The Chattahoochee Singing Convention, Pp. 1-22 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Research Materials---The Chattahoochee Singing Convention, Pp. 23-35 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Research Materials---The Chattahoochee Singing Convention, PP. 36-48 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Research Materials---The Chattahoochee Singing Convention, Pp. 49-61 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Research Materials---The Chattahoochee Singing Convention, Pp. 62-78 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Research Materials---The Chattahoochee Singing Convention, Pp. 79-94 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Research Materials---Folky Hymns, A to Lift (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Research Materials---Folky Hymns, Lord to Young (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Research Materials---“Peaceable Kingdom” by Randall Thompson (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Research Materials--- A typescript of “A Collection of Hymns for the Use of Primitive Methodists, 1822” (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Research Materials---Transcription of 77 Pennsylvania Dutch Spirituals (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Research Materials---Title of Secular Ballads and Songs Mentioned in Spiritual Folk Songs and Down East Ballads (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Research materials---“Hymns and Spirituals Songs” (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Research Materials---“Hymns and Spiritual Songs” (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Research Materials---“Hymns and Spiritual Songs” (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Research Materials---“Hymns and Spiritual Songs” (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Research Materials---“Hymns and Spiritual Songs” (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Research Materials—“Hymns and Spiritual Songs” (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Research Materials---Printed Songs (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Research Materials---Printed Songs (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Notes---Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Notes---Tune Index Explanation and List of Recordings (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Notes on Songs---“Early Odds and Ends” (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Notes on Songs---“Religious Folk Songs Not Used” and “Lily of the Valley Tune” (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Notes on Songs---“Captain Kidd” Song Family; “Judas Tree” Article Data (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Notes on Songs---“Surge Songs” (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Notes on Songs---School Songs, No Words; Songs in Process (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Notes on Songs---Tune Families (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Notes on Songs---Fosteriana; Negro Song Recordings (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Notes on Songs---Religious Folk Songs from the Oral Tradition (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Notes on Songs---Title, Introduction (School Songs); Second Choice School Songs (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Publications---A Bibliography of Jackson’s Publications, 1908-1950 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Publications---A Bibliography of The George Pullen Jackson of Southern Hymnody by Paul J. Revitt (The University of Southern California at Los Angeles)-2 copies (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Personal Information---A Tribute to George Pullen Jackson from the United Sacred Harp Singing Association, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Personal Information---Chronology; Additional Biographical and Professional Information (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Personal Information---A Sketch of Dean Tillett, Vanderbilt University by George Pullen Jackson, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Songs---Early Odds and Ends (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Songs---Religious Folk Songs Not Used in My Book (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Songs---Religious Folk Songs Not Used in My Book and “Lily of the Valley Tune” (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Songs---Religious Folk Songs Not Used in My Book (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Songs---Religious Folk Songs Not Used in My Book (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Songs---Religious Folk Songs Not Used in My Book (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Songs---“Lily of the Valley Tune” (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Songs---“Captain Kidd Song Family” (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Songs---“Captain Kidd song Family” (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Songs---“Judas Tree” Article Data (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Songs---“Judas Tree” Article Data (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Songs---“Surge Songs” (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Songs---“School Songs, No Words” (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Songs---“Songs in Process” (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Songs---First Selection of Songs for Sing, Brother, Sing (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Songs---First Selection of Songs for Sing, Brother, Sing (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Songs---Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Songs---Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Songs---Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Songs---Religious Folk Songs from Oral Tradition (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Songs---Religious Folk Songs from Oral Tradition (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Songs---Religious Folk Songs from Oral Tradition (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Songs---Religious Folk Songs from Oral Tradition (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Songs---Religious Folk Songs from Oral Tradition (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Songs---Religious Folk Songs from Oral Tradition (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Songs---Ideas for School Song Book (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Songs---Ideas for School Song Book (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Songs---Ideas for School Song Book (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Songs---Ideas for School Song Book (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Songs---Ideas fro School Song Book (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Songs---Ideas for School Song Book (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Songs---Ideas for School Song Book (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Songs---Ideas for School Song Book (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Songs---Ideas for School Song Book (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Songs---Ideas for School Song Book (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Songs---Ideas for School Song Book (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Songs---Negro Song Recordings (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Songs---Second Choice School Songs (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Songs---Second Choice School Songs (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Songs---Second Choice School Songs (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Songs---Second Choice School Songs (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Songs---Second Choice School Songs (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Songs---Second Choice School Songs (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Songs---Second Choice School Songs (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Songs---Second Choice School Songs (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Songs---Index to Titles, Subtitles, First Lines, and Tunes of Songs and Parts of Songs in Manuscript Form and Their Location within the Collection (Box 3 and Correspondence) (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Box 4 is a Card Box which contains an Index of Tunes (Box 4)
- Box 5 is a Card box which contains an Index of Tunes (Box 5)
- Box 6 is a Card Box which contains: 1. a Tune Index; 2. Note Cards (Box 6)
- Box 7 is a Card Box which contains: 1. Note Cards; 2. an alphabetical bibliography of Hymn and Tune Books; 3. a Sacred Harp Singers Directory (Box 7)
- Box 8 is a Card Box which contains: 1. Sacred Harp Singers Directory; 2. Sacred Harp Singers and Nashville Music Meeting, 1952; 3. Chronological File of Hymn Books, 1737-1839 (Box 8)
- Box 9 is a Card Box which contains: 1. Excerpts from Song Books; 2. Alphabetical File of Song Titles (Box 9)
- Box 10 is a Card Box which contains an Alphabetical File of Song Titles (Box 10)
- Records---“The Mary Golden Tree” (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Records---“The Mary Golden Tree” (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Records---“The Mary Golden Tree” (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Records---“Jesus Born in Bethlehem”; “Evening Shade” (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Records---“Jesus Born in Bethlehem”; Evening Shade” (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Records---“Jesus Born in Bethlehem”; “Evening Shade” (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Records---“All Is Well”; “Soldier Won’t You Marry Me?” (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Records---“All Is Well”; “Soldier Won’t You Marry Me?” (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Records---”All Is Well”; “Soldier Won’t You Marry Me?” (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Records---“Poor Wayfaring Stranger” (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Records---“Poor Wayfaring Stranger” (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Records---“Poor Wayfaring Stranger” (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Records---“Poor Wayfaring Stranger”; “Evening Shade”; “Hosanna to Jesus” (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Records---“Pretty Little Miss”; Frog Went A’Courting” (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Records---“Old Ship of Zion”; “Boundless Mercy” (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Records---Fillmore; New Britain (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Records---Blooming Youth; The Good Old Way (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Records---Raymond; Ragan (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Records---The Christian’s Hope; Mount Zion (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Records---Reverential Anthem; Resurrected (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Records---Passing Away; Exhortation (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Records---Lullaby; Spotless Rose (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Records---Wondrous Love; Lover of the Lord (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Recordings 9-14 Are Described in Detail in “Surge Songs”, Box 2, File 30 and Box 3, File 12 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Records---Pleasant Valley Primitive Baptist Church (Negro) (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Records---Pleasant Valley Primitive Baptist Church (Negro) (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Records---Pleasant Valley Primitive Baptist Church (Negro) (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Records---Pleasant Valley Primitive Baptist Church (Negro) (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Records---Pleasant Valley Primitive Baptist Church (Negro) (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Records---Pleasant Valley Primitive Baptist Church (Negro) (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Records---Blank Record (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Records---Blank Record (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Records---Blank Record (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Reel to Reel Tapes---Tape 1: (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Side 1-All Is Well; Soldier Won’t You marry Me; Hebrew Children; When God’s Awful Trump (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Barnyard Song; Springfield Mountain; Blooming Youth; The Good Old Way; Mt. Zion (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Side 2-Mt. Zion; Christian’s Hope; The Mary Golden Tree; Springfield Mountain; Fillmore (Box 12, Folder 18)
- New Britain; The Frog Went A’Courting; Sourwood Mountain; Jesus Born in Bethlehem (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Evening Shade (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Reel to Reel Tapes---Tape 2: (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Side 1-Evening Shade; Spotless Rose; The Mary Golden Tree; Old Ship of Zion; Boundless (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Mercy; Passing Away; Exhortation; Poor Wayfaring Stranger (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Side 2-Poor Wayfaring Stranger; Old Ship of Zion; Evening Shade; Hosanna to Jesus; Pretty (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Little Miss; Frog Went A’Courting; Soldier, Soldier; Ragan; Raymond; Resurrected (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Reel to Reel Tapes---Tape 3: (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Side 1-Pleasant Valley Primitive Baptist Church (Negro) (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Side 2-Alabama; Old Fashioned Bible; Milford; Claremont; David’s Lamentation (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Mission, Heavenly Vision; Sherburne; Jackson’s Talk; Evening Shade; Lover of the Lord (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Reel to Reel Tapes-Tape 4: (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Side 1-Ballstown; Fillmore; Evening Shade; Mear; Stratfield; Windham; Sardis (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Mt. Zion (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Side 2-Mt. Zion; David’s Lamentation; Northfield; Ortonville; Sardis (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Cassette Tapes-Tape 1: (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Side 1-The Mary Golden Tree; Jesus Born in Bethlehem; Evening Shade (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Side 2-All Is Well; Soldier Won’t You Marry Me; Poor Wayfaring Stranger (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Cassette Tapes-Tape 2: (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Side 1-Poor Wayfaring Stranger; Evening Shade; Hosanna to Jesus; Pretty Little Miss (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Frog Went A’Courting; Soldier Won’t You Marry Me; Old Ship of Zion; Boundless Mercy (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Records---Fillmore; New Britain (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Records---Blooming Youth; The Good Old Way (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Records---Raymond; Ragan (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Records---The Christian’s Hope; Mount Zion (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Records---Reverential Anthem; Resurrected (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Records---Passing Away; Exhortation (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Records---Lullaby; Spotless Rose (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Records---Wondrous Love; Lover of the Lord (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Recordings 9-14 Are Described in Detail in “Surge Songs”, Box 2, File 30 and Box 3, File 12 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Records---Pleasant Valley Primitive Baptist Church (Negro) (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Records---Pleasant Valley Primitive Baptist Church (Negro) (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Records---Pleasant Valley Primitive Baptist Church (Negro) (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Records---Pleasant Valley Primitive Baptist Church (Negro) (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Records---Pleasant Valley Primitive Baptist Church (Negro) (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Records---Pleasant Valley Primitive Baptist Church (Negro) (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Records---Blank Record (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Records---Blank Record (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Records---Blank Record (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Reel to Reel Tapes---Tape 1: (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Side 1-All Is Well; Soldier Won’t You marry Me; Hebrew Children; When God’s Awful Trump (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Barnyard Song; Springfield Mountain; Blooming Youth; The Good Old Way; Mt. Zion (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Side 2-Mt. Zion; Christian’s Hope; The Mary Golden Tree; Springfield Mountain; Fillmore (Box 12, Folder 18)
- New Britain; The Frog Went A’Courting; Sourwood Mountain; Jesus Born in Bethlehem (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Evening Shade (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Reel to Reel Tapes---Tape 2: (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Side 1-Evening Shade; Spotless Rose; The Mary Golden Tree; Old Ship of Zion; Boundless (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Mercy; Passing Away; Exhortation; Poor Wayfaring Stranger (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Side 2-Poor Wayfaring Stranger; Old Ship of Zion; Evening Shade; Hosanna to Jesus; Pretty (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Little Miss; Frog Went A’Courting; Soldier, Soldier; Ragan; Raymond; Resurrected (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Reel to Reel Tapes---Tape 3: (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Side 1-Pleasant Valley Primitive Baptist Church (Negro) (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Side 2-Alabama; Old Fashioned Bible; Milford; Claremont; David’s Lamentation (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Mission, Heavenly Vision; Sherburne; Jackson’s Talk; Evening Shade; Lover of the Lord (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Reel to Reel Tapes-Tape 4: (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Side 1-Ballstown; Fillmore; Evening Shade; Mear; Stratfield; Windham; Sardis (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Mt. Zion (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Side 2-Mt. Zion; David’s Lamentation; Northfield; Ortonville; Sardis (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Cassette Tapes-Tape 1: (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Side 1-The Mary Golden Tree; Jesus Born in Bethlehem; Evening Shade (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Side 2-All Is Well; Soldier Won’t You Marry Me; Poor Wayfaring Stranger (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Cassette Tapes-Tape 2: (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Side 1-Poor Wayfaring Stranger; Evening Shade; Hosanna to Jesus; Pretty Little Miss (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Frog Went A’Courting; Soldier Won’t You Marry Me; Old Ship of Zion; Boundless Mercy (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Records--- David’s Lamentation; Northfield; Ortonville; Schenectady (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Records---Claremont; David’s Lamentation (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Records---Stratfield; Windham; Sardis; Mt. Zion (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Records---Mission; Heavenly Vision; Sherburne (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Records---Evening Shade; Mear; Ballstown; Fillmore (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Records---Jackson’s Talk; Evening Shade; Lover of the Lord (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Records---Frog Went A’Courting; Sourwood Mountain (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Records---The Barnyard Song; Springfield Mountain (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Records---Schenectady; The Trees Do Moan (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Records---The Mary Golden Tree; Springfield Mountain (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Records---The Old Ship of Zion; Poor Wayfaring Stranger (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Records---Hebrew Children; When Gabriel’s Awful Trump; All Is Well (Box 13, Folder 12)
An Alphabetical Index to Titles, Subtitles, First Lines, and Tunes of Songs and Parts of Songs in Manuscript Form---and Their Location Within the Collection in Box 3 ( C Numbers Refer to Correspondence Folders in Box 1 )
The Abolition Show, 18
Ach du Miser Judas, 10
Admiral Benbow, 9
Admiral Byng and Brave West, 9, C7
Afflictions, though they seem severe, C1
Afton Water, 17
Alas, and did my savior bleed, 2, 6
All hail to thee, Christ Jesus, 10
All Is Well, 29
Amanda, 25
Amazing Grace, 5,6,C17
An’ Pharoah’s daughter went down to the water, 22
And how should I your true love know, 40
The Arethusa, 19
Army of the Lord, 2
Around the throne of God in heaven, 6
As I passed the garden, 25
As I stepped out one evening, 11
As I walked out one morning, 44
As shepherds in Jewry were guarding their sheep, 44
The Ass’s Sequence, 40
Awake, Awake, you drowsy sleeper, 32
Away here in Texas, 42
Balow, my babe, lye still and sleep, 34
Banks of Cloddy, 11
The Banks of Sweet Dundee, 41
The Banks of the Shannon, 33
Barbara Allen, 43
Beautiful Way –missing from the collection
Behold the rose of Sharon here, 20
Billy Boy, 43
The Black Brigade, 37
The Blessings of Mary, C10
The Boatie Rows, 17
Bonapart’s Exile, 36
Boney’s away from his wars and his fighting, 36